<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dagupan Festival </string>
    <string name="history">
        <br>
            History of Dagupan</br>
        </string>
    <string name="description">
        <br>
            If you’d ask where the Bangus Festival place is, many Filipinos would already know the answer as
            there is only one place in the country that is known to have the tastiest bangus: Dagupan. You can
            trace the Bangus Festival history back to 2002 when it all started. It was then-Mayor Benjamin Lim who
            initiated this kind of festival to promote Dagupan’s most precious gem, bangus or milkfish. And one year
            later, they were recognized Kalutan ed Dagupan by the Guinness Book of World Records as the Longest
            Barbecue of the World.


            Since then, Dagupan has been celebrating this festivity yearly in the month of April. In fact, because
            it is a big event, many media entities not just from the Philippines but across the world
            are covering this annual event in Dagupan.</br>
        </string>
    <string name="bangusine"><br>101 Ways to Cook Bangus</br>
    </string>
    <string name="eventdescription1">
        <br> It is a cooking contest where seasoned cooks or chefs showcase their talent
            preparing the bangus in the most unique and delicious way.In this event, the
            contestants who participate in this event will compete in cooking skills using
            the main ingredients. The bangus will be presented. The winner will take home a
            large prize.</br>
    </string>

    <string name="streetdance"><br>Gilon! Gilon! ed Dalan</br></string>
    <string name="descrip2">
        The Gilon-Gilon ed Dalan street dance competition is one of the main events of Dagupan\'s
        annual Bangus Festival. 31 barangays demonstrate their artistic interpretation of harvesting
        fish (gilon-gilon in the Pangasinan language) through dance and costume.
        Like any other festivals, of course it’s not complete without street dancing. When the Bangus
        Festival takes place, the participants wear colorful Bangus Festival costumes and dance to the beat
        of the drums where some even carry bangus props.
    </string>
    <string name="rodeo">Bangus Rodeo </string>
    <string name="descrip3">
        <br>
        The Bangus Rodeo is one of the traditional Bangus Festival events since
        its launching 2002 by then mayor, the late Benjamin Lim. ... The owner of the prettiest bangus
        will receive PHP7,000 and trophy. First and second runners-up will get PHP5,000 and trophy and
        PHP3,000 plus trophy, respectively.This is the event where the bangus growers showcase their best
        products and their food-processing skills.</br>
    </string>
    <string name="kalutan">Kalutan ed Dagupan</string>
    <string name="descrip4"><br>
        THE Kalutan ed Dalan Street Party of the Bangus Festival held on April 30 this city, is the biggest
        street party.Some 14,000 pieces or 4,500 kilos of bangus were grilled in 900 grill pads that
        were sold to various groups by the city government, packaged with charcoal, hotdogs, s
        oda and tent.
        This is one of the main highlights of the event. That is why when Bangus Festival 2020 didn’t happen
        due to the pandemic, the yearly tradition was cut. Kalitan ed Dagupan is the event where everyone partakes
        in grilling thousands of bangus on the street.
    </br></string>
    <string name="festivalofnorth">Festival of north</string>
    <string name="descrip5"><br>
        it is also one of the highly anticipated events in the festival where the critics
        will mourn in various places carrying and representing their city and their proud
        product within the region1. they will fight against it through a street dancing which
        also includes dagupan. the winner will get a big prize</br></string>

    <string name="historydescription">The Bangus Festival is one of the major and most exciting festivals in the Philippines worth
        visiting and coming back for. Watch and enjoy the Gilon-Gilon ed Dalan, a street dancing competition; 101 Ways to Cook Bangus;
        Bangus Rodeo; Bangus ed Karosa; and the Kalutan ed Dalan, which earned for Dagupan City the Guiness World Record as the
        longest grill in 2003.Undeniably, the Bangus Festival has become the best advertisement for the world’s tastiest milkfish;
        the Dagupan Bangus.The Agew na Dagupan is celebrated on the day when Dagupan was chartered as a city on June 20, 1947 when
        President Manuel A. Roxas signed into law Republic Acr 170 authored by then Speaker Eugenio Perez. On October 13, 1947,
        President Roxas issued Executive Order No. 96 implementing Republic Act 170 and fixing the territorial limits of the
        city. The celebration of the Agew na Dagupan, or the founding day of Dagupan is observed as a holiday
        with appropriate rites.Dagupan City starts the Dagupan City Fiesta in honor of the city’s patron St. John
        the Evangelist on December 16, with the traditional misa de gallo. Christmas has become synonymous to the
        Dagupan Fiesta wherein institutionalized activities mark nightly events at the City Plaza such as Nights
        for Employees, Rotarians, Barangays, alumni of Dagupan City National High School, Teachers and
        Professionals, Balikbayans, Miss Dagupan Coronation Night and the Rizal Day Celebration. Hundreds
        of overseas Dagupenos also make an annual trip back home under the city’s Pawil Dagupan Project.
        December 27 is the feast day of St. John the Evangelist.</string>


    <string name="streetparty">Dagupan Street Party</string>
    <string name="descrip6">
        <br>
            this is really the most anticipated by the people in the bangus festival where the heavy
            personalities will perform on a single stage which is held on the road which is one of the
            most events of the bangus festival and because of this many people come to the event this to
            see a heavyweight personality in the industry
        </br>
    </string>


</resources>